[Music]
[音樂]
This is a 62-year-old man. We're going
這是一位62歲的老人。我們
to call him
就叫他
James. James is trying to sleep, but
詹姆斯吧。詹姆斯想睡覺，但
he's rolling around in bed, sleepless.
他輾轉反側，難以入眠。
So, he'll get out of bed, watch TV. He's
所以，他會起床，看電視。他是
what you call a regular guy in his 60s,
個很普通的六十多歲男人，
but he doesn't interact with that many
但他不怎麼和
people. He doesn't have a job. He
人打交道。他沒有工作。他
doesn't have a wife or a partner, nor
沒有妻子或伴侶，
does he have children at home.
家裡也沒有孩子。
Basically, he's pretty isolated. We know
基本上，他與世隔絕。
of other people because of the American
由於美國
Time use survey. For 20 years, the
時間使用調查，我們和成千上萬其他人一樣，都知道詹姆斯在做什麼。 20年來，美國
Bureau of Labor Statistics has a select
勞工統計局一直挑選
group of people track how they spend
一部分人來追蹤他們如何度過
time. Here's a journal for a 36-year-old
時間。這是一位36歲男子的日記
man. On this day, he wakes up at 7:00
。這一天，他早上7點起床，
a.m. He feeds his kids. He goes to work.
餵孩子吃飯。他去上班了。
Every hour or so, he'll journal what
他大約每隔一小時就會把
he's
自己正在
doing. We'll use these daily journals,
做的事情記錄下來。我們將使用這些
all from a typical weekday in 2021, to
來自 2021 年典型工作日的每日日誌，來
follow a handful of people, including
追蹤包括 James 在內的幾個人
James.
。
This is everyone's time log from 7:00
這是大家早上7點開始的時間紀錄。
a.m. So, they're all just waking up. And
所以，他們都剛起床。到了晚上，大家
by the end of everyone's day, we'll
就會
learn that James' isolation is a far
發現，詹姆斯的孤獨其實是一種
more common
更普遍的
experience. We all personally know about
體驗。我們每個人身邊大約有
500 people, but many of these people
500 個人，但這些人中很多
aren't going to help us in times of
在我們需要幫助的時候並不會伸出援手
need. The people who are actually going
。真正會
to help us are our friends. And among
幫助我們的人是我們的朋友。在
all those friends, there's about 15
所有這些朋友中，大約有 15 位
friends and family we'll regularly stay
親朋好友我們會定期保持
in contact with. And one or two of those
聯繫。這些
people might even be in an intimate
人中甚至可能有一兩個人是親密
relationship, such as a partner or best
關係，例如伴侶或最好的
friend. Let's get back to our group.
朋友。我們回到小組討論吧。  現在
It's 8:00 a.m. and the whole group is
是早上8點，整個團隊都在
going about their morning. And we see
忙著各自的晨間活動。我們看到，
here that some people are beginning to
有些人開始
interact with friends and family. We're
與朋友和家人互動。我們
going to make this easier to see by
將用
shading friends and family in bright
亮紫色陰影標出朋友和家人，使畫面更清晰
purple, like the four kids around the
，就像圖中這位女士周圍的四個孩子一樣
woman here. This is a 22-year-old man
。這位是22歲的男子
over here, and he said that he's
，他說他和
traveling with two parents and four
父母以及四個
siblings. And this 37year-old woman over
兄弟姐妹一起旅行。這位37歲的女士正在
here, she's preparing food with her
和她的
spouse and child.
丈夫、孩子一起準備食物。  在社交互動方面，
Everyone has different needs when it
每個人的需求都不同
comes to social interaction. So, we're
。所以，我們
going to add that metric to our group.
將把這個指標加入我們的群組。
On the Y-axis over here is how much time
Y軸表示
each person spent with friends or family
每個人在當天與朋友或家人相處的時間
on this particular day. Now, we can see
。現在，我們可以看到
social interaction accumulating. And
社交互動不斷累積。隨著時間的推移，
here, the yellow bars are slowly
黃色長條圖正在緩慢
creeping up as the morning
上升
progresses. Let's check in on James
。我們再來看看詹姆斯的情況
again. It's 11:40 a.m. and he writes
。現在是上午 11:40，他寫道，
that he's come home from the grocery
他已經從雜貨店回家，
store and he's preparing lunch. After
正在準備午餐。
lunch, he's going to watch TV again.
午飯後，他打算再看一次電視。  他
He's been around other people today,
今天也和其他人接觸過，
like at the grocery store, but it's 1:00
例如去了雜貨店，但現在是下午1點。他其實
p.m. and he hasn't really done much with
沒怎麼跟
other people. People will generally
其他人合作過。人們通常會
under reportport loneliness, mostly due
低估孤獨感，這主要是由於
to the stigma of social isolation. So,
社會孤立帶來的恥辱感。那麼，
let's go back to the time you survey and
讓我們回到你做調查的時候，
look at some data. Going back all the
看看一些數據。
way to 2003, we can see here the amount
追溯到 2003 年，我們可以看到，
of time middle-aged and older people
中年人和老年人
spend with family dropped by 10%. But
與家人相處的時間減少了 10%。但
for those under 34 years old, the drop
對於 34 歲以下的人來說，降幅
was three times higher, down by 30%. And
是原來的三倍，下降了 30%。
the time we spend with friends also went
我們和朋友相處的時間也
down. And again, it hits young people
減少了。而且，它對年輕人的打擊
especially hard. They're spending about
尤其嚴重。他們現在花在
half as much time with friends as they
朋友身上的時間只有
did 20 years ago. And the amount of time
20年前的一半左右。
we spend alone went up across every age
各個年齡層的
group. Elderly people have always been
人獨處的時間都在增加。老年人一直處於
isolated, but even that's gotten worse.
孤立狀態，但這種情況現在變得更糟了。  獨處
Now, being alone isn't necessarily the
不一定等於
same thing as being lonely, but
孤獨，但
according to a meta analysis of studies,
根據一項研究的統合分析，
every year more and more people are
每年都有越來越多的人
reporting that they're lonely, a trend
表示自己感到孤獨，這一趨勢
that's held true since 1976.
自 1976 年以來一直持續至今。
Returning to our time use survey, it's
回到我們的時間利用調查，現在是
3:30 in the afternoon and a lot of the
下午 3:30，許多
boxes, they're still dark on this
方框在這一天仍然一片漆黑
particular day. Just like James, all
。和詹姆斯一樣，
these people have yet to report any
這些人目前都還沒有報告
interaction with friends and
與朋友和
family. Social isolation increases
家人有任何接觸。社會孤立會使
premature death by 50%. That's the same
過早死亡人數增加 50%。這相當於
effect as smoking 15 cigarettes a day or
每天抽15支煙或
having six drinks a
每天喝6杯酒
day. There's actually a really important
。實際上，
question from the time you survey that I
我想談談你們調查中提出的一個非常重要的問題。事情是這樣的。
Imagine a ladder. The top of the ladder
想像梯子。人生的巔峰
is your best possible life. The bottom
就是你所能擁有的最美好的生活。最底層代表
is your worst possible life. The
你最糟糕的人生。
question goes, "Which step of the ladder
問題是：「
do you feel you personally stand on at
你覺得自己目前站在梯子的哪一級？
time?" This is called the Caner ladder.
」這被稱為坎納階梯。
In the US, most people answer on the
在美國，大多數人的回答都比較
positive side, a 7 out of 10 on
積極，平均得分為 7 分（滿分 10 分）
average. Where are you on this
。你在這架
ladder? According to James' time log,
梯子上的位置在哪裡？根據詹姆斯的作息紀錄，
he'll keep watching TV until about 8:30
他會一直看電視到晚上8點半左右。
p.m. He then goes to sleep without
然後他就睡著了，期間沒有
having interacted with anyone. the
和任何人交流。一
day. When James answers where he was on
整天。當詹姆斯回答
the Kantrol letter, he said he was a
坎特羅爾信中他當時的處境時，他說他當時
zero, his worst possible
一無所有，過著最糟糕的
life. Let's go back to the group and
生活。讓我們回到小組，
look at where they are on the Kentra
看看他們在 Kentra
letter. First, we'll sort everyone from
信件上的位置。首先，我們將所有人按排名
highest to
從高到低排序，
lowest and then add their ladder number
然後將他們的排名編號加到
right over here to each person's
每個人的
box. Even in this small data set, you
方框中。即使在這麼小的資料集中，你也能
see the difference, right? The bottom
看出差別，對吧？
half here all answered that they were
這裡排名靠後的一半受訪者都表示，他們的排名在
three or lower on the ladder and many of
第三或更低，而且
them have yet to interact with anyone on
他們中的許多人在當天還沒有與任何人互動過
day. It's a lot easier to see this when
。當
we look at aggregate data from the
我們查看週末的匯總數據時，這一點就更容易看出來了
weekends. Here we see lines go up as
。在這裡我們可以看到，隨著
people spend more time with others.
人們與他人相處時間的增加，排隊的人數也會增加。
These lines are just for those who said
這些話只適用於那些自稱
they were at the top or middle of the
處於事業頂峰或中層的人
ladder. Now let's look at those who rate
。現在讓我們來看看那些對
their lives lowest on the ladder. And
自己的生活評價最低的人。
that's right, they spend more of their
沒錯，他們更多的時間都是
weekends alone.
獨自度過的。
It's such a cruel twist that loneliness
真是諷刺，孤獨反而
makes socializing feel more
讓社交變得更具
threatening. Former US surgeon Merti
威脅性。美國前外科醫生梅爾蒂
once said, "Over time, this vicious
曾說：「隨著時間的推移，這種惡性
cycle may convince us we don't matter to
循環可能會讓我們相信，我們對
anyone, that we're unworthy of
任何人來說都無關緊要，我們不配得到
love." Humans evolved to survive in
愛。」人類進化是為了在群體中生存
groups. So when we're isolated, we're
。所以當我們被隔離時，我們會覺得自己處於
convinced that we're in danger. So
危險之中。所以，
talking about loneliness means telling
談論孤獨意味著告訴
someone that you're hurting on a primal
別人你內心深處感到痛苦
level.
。
So, we don't talk about it and it stays
所以，我們不談論它，它就一直被
invisible. I see myself and so many
忽略。我在這個故事裡看到了自己和很多
people in this story and if they're
人，如果他們和我一樣，他們
anything like me, they're not telling
不會告訴
anyone they're lonely or even admitting
任何人他們感到孤獨，甚至不會向自己承認
it to
這一點
themselves. I want to be around people
。我希望身邊都是關心我的人，
who care about me and I want to be able
我也希望能夠
to take care of them, too.
照顧他們。
But really, I just don't want to fall
但說真的，我只是不想帶著
asleep feeling like I'm alone.
孤獨感入睡。